<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
   
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<p>New feature summary for GW Maven Plugin 1.1.8-SNAPSHOT:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Integrated Ghostwriter guided file processing into Maven goals for repeatable project file updates.</li>
  <li>Added prompt-driven act workflows, including reusable act definitions and interactive act input.</li>
  <li>Added execution-root and per-module goals for guided and act-based processing across Maven reactor projects.</li>
  <li>Added Maven settings integration for provider credentials via <code>genai.serverId</code>.</li>
  <li>Added configurable processing options for model selection, scan directories, instructions, exclusions, act locations, action prompts, threading, and input logging.</li>
  <li>Added Java class discovery and reflective inspection tools for project-aware AI-assisted analysis.</li>
  <li>Added a cleanup goal for removing temporary workflow artifacts.</li>
</ul>

## Features

- Integrated Ghostwriter guided file processing directly into Maven goals for repeatable source, documentation, and site updates.
- Added prompt-driven act workflows with support for reusable act definitions and interactive input when no explicit action prompt is supplied.
- Added execution-root and per-module goal variants for guided and act-based processing in standard Maven reactor workflows.
- Added support for reverse-order execution-root guided processing so submodules can be processed before parent projects.
- Added support for running the main guided goal without requiring a Maven project in the current directory.
- Added Maven <code>settings.xml</code> integration for provider credentials and custom configuration via <code>genai.serverId</code>.
- Added configurable processing parameters for model selection, scan roots, instructions, exclusions, act locations, prompts, threading, and input logging.
- Added Java class discovery and reflective inspection function tools for project-aware analysis, including class matching, member metadata, source paths, and dependency artifact origins.
- Added a cleanup goal for removing temporary Ghostwriter workflow artifacts.
]]></action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>