<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
     <release version="1.1.14" date="2026-05-24">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Features:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Added dedicated embedding provider abstraction and manager lookup for embedding-specific operations.</li>
  <li>Added EmbeddingProvider type validation before instantiation in GenaiProviderManager.</li>
  <li>Refactored embedding support across OpenAI and CodeMie providers with delegated embedding calls.</li>
  <li>Added instructions and model parameter handling in ActMojo.</li>
  <li>Added HTML parsing and text processing utilities dependencies.</li>
</ul>
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed variable names in Ghostwriter processor.</li>
  <li>Fixed classification JSON detection in Picker and updated embedding model provider prefix in assembly act.</li>
  <li>Fixed missing return statement in embedding method of CodeMieProvider.</li>
  <li>Fixed null checks to prevent overwriting instructions and model properties in ActProcessor.</li>
  <li>Added fallback to System.out.print for null console and model logging in Ghostwriter.</li>
</ul>
<b>Refactoring:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Removed unused listFilesRecursively method and fixed unchecked cast warning in ProjectContextFunctionTools.</li>
  <li>Removed unused imports from CodeMieProvider and BindexFunctionTools.</li>
  <li>Removed unused dependencies from pom.xml.</li>
  <li>Refactored CodeMieProvider to use named inner classes for provider extensions.</li>
  <li>Refactored provider initialization to pass model name as explicit parameter instead of through configuration.</li>
  <li>Refactored maven-javadoc-plugin configuration from reporting to pluginManagement section.</li>
  <li>Refactored bindex act to use multi-step inputs with dedicated javadoc generation.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.13" date="2026-05-22">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Updated interactive prompt logging constants for more consistent prompt-related output.</li>
  <li>Refactored usage statistics logging across Maven plugin mojos to improve logging behavior and maintainability.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
     <release version="1.1.10" date="2026-05-12">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Improved commit handling and interactive exit flow for more reliable plugin execution.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.9" date="2026-05-10">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Updated task termination handling across Maven goals for improved execution stability.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.8" date="2026-05-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed initialization of <code>ClassFunctionalTools</code>.</li>
  <li>Applied additional Sonar-related fixes.</li>
</ul>
<b>Chores:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Improved project layout handling by adding exclude directory propagation, using project layout file discovery for recursive file listing, supporting multi-MCP definitions, and renaming <code>ProcessTerminationException</code> to <code>TaskTerminationException</code>.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Features:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Integrated Ghostwriter guided file processing directly into Maven goals for repeatable source, documentation, and site updates.
  <li>Added prompt-driven act workflows with support for reusable act definitions and interactive input when no explicit action prompt is supplied.
  <li>Added execution-root and per-module goal variants for guided and act-based processing in standard Maven reactor workflows.
  <li>Added support for reverse-order execution-root guided processing so submodules can be processed before parent projects.</li>
  <li>Added support for running the main guided goal without requiring a Maven project in the current directory.</li>
  <li>Added Maven <code>settings.xml</code> integration for provider credentials and custom configuration via <code>genai.serverId</code>.</li>
  <li>Added configurable processing parameters for model selection, scan roots, instructions, exclusions, act locations, prompts, threading, and input logging.</li>
  <li>Added Java class discovery and reflective inspection function tools for project-aware analysis, including class matching, member metadata, source paths, and dependency artifact origins.</li>
  <li>Added a cleanup goal for removing temporary Ghostwriter workflow artifacts.</li>
</ul>
]]></action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>