<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-03-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Initial release of the GW Maven Plugin, providing the <code>gw</code> goal for AI-assisted project processing and code/documentation generation.</li>
  <li>GenAI provider support and configuration (including OpenAI-compatible providers and CodeMie integration), with request timeouts and usage logging.</li>
  <li>Instruction and guidance support via files and CLI properties/options, with default guidance handling and path matching/glob/regex support.</li>
  <li>Multi-threaded module processing with configurable timeouts and improved command execution/output handling.</li>
  <li>Packaging and distribution improvements (delivery pack/zip and Maven assembly packaging profiles).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Resolved numerous path/root-directory and scanning issues (scanDir processing, root project execution, file ordering/sorting, exclusion handling, and non-path pattern matching).</li>
  <li>Fixed null handling and NPEs in configuration and processing flows; improved error and log messages.</li>
  <li>Corrected CLI/help text and option processing (threads, guidance, instructions/excludes parsing, serverId optionality).</li>
  <li>Improved provider robustness (OpenAI request timeout, CodeMie authUrl handling, synchronized web calls).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Extracted and reorganized components (project layout handling, function tools, provider interfaces/manager) and cleaned up dependencies/imports.</li>
  <li>Renamed and standardized modules/goals/packages (e.g., plugin goal to <code>gw</code>, package renames, configurator usage).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added and updated extensive documentation (README/site pages, Javadoc, guidance examples, prompt templates) and improved download/help references.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Version bumps and release preparations across multiple snapshot/release iterations leading to 1.0.0.</li>
  <li>Build/test maintenance (test updates/disablements, pack profile adjustments, logging output tweaks).</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-03-14">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added support for loading <code>acts</code> locations from URLs.</li>
  <li>Improved concurrency handling for GW/Act execution and extended CLI options for <code>ActCommand</code> and <code>GWCommand</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed <code>nonRecursive</code> mode processing.</li>
  <li>Improved Act prompt parsing and <code>scanDir</code> resolution.</li>
  <li>Sonar-related fixes applied via <code>gw:act</code> (<code>sonar-fix</code>).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Aligned the Maven Act goal option naming/behavior for <code>acts</code> location and performed minor import optimizations.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.2" date="2026-03-23">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added unit tests for <code>gw-maven-plugin</code>.</li>
  <li>Updated reactor build behavior to scan documents correctly in multi-module builds.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed GenAI model property naming.</li>
  <li>Fixed null-safe formatting fallback for Act input templates.</li>
  <li>Adjusted processors to use the project directory consistently (replacing <code>gw.rootDir</code> usage; renamed <code>rootDir</code> to <code>projectDir</code>; aligned CLI option to <code>--project.dir</code>/<code>-d</code>).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Refactored GW model variable naming and standardized line-feed handling (use <code>StringUtils.LF</code>).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated documentation alongside the GenAI model property rename.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Removed the effective POM requirement toggle.</li>
  <li>Updated <code>bindex.json</code> files and cleaned up Sonar comments.</li>
  <li>Maintenance updates from automated <code>gw:gw</code> runs.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.3" date="2026-03-30">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added Maven plugin integration tests for Act/GW goals.</li>
  <li>Improved Act handling and behavior, including prompt label casing and prompt restore in reactor executions.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed property constant usage across plugin goals (including <code>logInputs</code>, Ghostwriter constants, Act constants, and line separator handling).</li>
  <li>Fixed scan exclusion handling and deferred root scan logging.</li>
  <li>Fixed custom/override <code>acts</code> location resolution and related Act goal logging/messages.</li>
  <li>Fixed guidance tag definition and PlantUML Maven plugin configuration.</li>
  <li>Removed support for <code>gw.rootProjectLast</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated site docs, Javadoc (including overview formatting guidance), and related tests/documents.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Normalized GW plugin line endings.</li>
  <li>Updated <code>bindex.json</code> metadata files.</li>
  <li>General maintenance updates to GenAI settings mapping and test coverage.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
