<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<ul>
  <li>Added documentation for standardized project folder modeling across sources, resources, tests, and documentation directories.</li>
  <li>Documented built-in layout definitions for Maven, Gradle, JavaScript, Python, and default project structures.</li>
  <li>Added guidance for resolving layout paths relative to a project base directory and deriving layout metadata from project files such as pom.xml.</li>
</ul>
      ]]></action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.8" date="2026-05-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed multi MCP server handling in <code>addMcpServer()</code>.</li>
  <li>Resolved Sonar-reported issues to improve code quality and maintainability.</li>
</ul>
<b>Refactoring:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Renamed <code>ProcessTerminationException</code> to <code>TaskTerminationException</code>.</li>
  <li>Updated recursive file lookup to use <code>ProjectLayout.findFiles(directory)</code> in the functional tool implementation.</li>
</ul>
<b>Chores:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Added <code>ProjectLayout.getExcludeDirs()</code> to final and system instructions, including <code>.machai</code> in the excluded directories list.</li>
  <li>Added automated tests and refreshed release notes for version 1.1.8.</li>
</ul>
      ]]></action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.12" date="2026-05-18">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Improved episode template prompt handling for user input.</li>
  <li>Standardized log messages by using backticks instead of single quotes.</li>
</ul>
      ]]></action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.13" date="2026-05-22">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Adjusted module processing logging levels.</li>
</ul>
      ]]></action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.14" date="2026-05-23">
      <action dev="dev" type="add"><![CDATA[
<b>Features:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Added dedicated embedding provider abstraction and manager lookup.</li>
  <li>Added dedicated embedding provider usage in Picker and removed schema function tool.</li>
  <li>Added instructions and model parameter handling in ActMojo.</li>
  <li>Enhanced readLine method to support multi-line input with line breaker and user signature.</li>
  <li>Added dependencies for HTML parsing and text processing utilities.</li>
</ul>
<b>Fixes:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed a variable name.</li>
  <li>Fixed classification JSON detection in Picker and updated embedding model provider prefix in assembly act.</li>
  <li>Added fallback to System.out.print for null console and model logging in Ghostwriter.</li>
  <li>Added null checks to prevent overwriting instructions and model properties in ActProcessor.</li>
  <li>Added EmbeddingProvider type validation before instantiation in GenaiProviderManager.</li>
</ul>
<b>Refactoring:</b>
<ul>
  <li>Refactored embedding support across OpenAI and CodeMie providers.</li>
  <li>Refactored CodeMieProvider to use named inner classes for provider extensions and fixed missing return statement in embedding method.</li>
  <li>Refactored provider initialization to pass model name as explicit parameter instead of through configuration.</li>
  <li>Refactored bindex act to use multi-step inputs with dedicated javadoc generation.</li>
  <li>Refactored maven-javadoc-plugin configuration from reporting to pluginManagement section.</li>
  <li>Removed unused listFilesRecursively method and fixed unchecked cast warning in ProjectContextFunctionTools.</li>
  <li>Removed unused imports from CodeMieProvider and BindexFunctionTools.</li>
  <li>Removed unused dependencies from pom.xml.</li>
</ul>
      ]]></action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
