<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-03-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Initial release of Machai: a modular toolkit for GenAI-enabled developer automation (Java libraries, CLI, and Maven plugins).</li>
  <li>Provider-agnostic GenAI client with pluggable providers (OpenAI, Gemini, Claude, CodeMie, None) and function-tool support (file/web/command), including safety denylist checks.</li>
  <li>Bindex metadata tooling to generate/consume library discovery indexes (schema + repository + builders) with Maven plugin and CLI integration.</li>
  <li>Ghostwriter automation for repo-scale documentation updates driven by embedded <code>@guidance</code>, with file processors and language reviewers (Java/Markdown/HTML/Python/TypeScript/PUML).</li>
  <li>Act system for reusable automation templates (TOML-based), including built-in acts such as commit, prompt, unit-tests, release-notes, sonar-fix, and grype-fix; supports custom act directories and non-interactive execution.</li>
  <li>Maven plugins for Ghostwriter/Acts (including reactor goals) and assembly support, plus project-layout detection for Maven/JS/Gradle-style projects.</li>
  <li>Project documentation site with module guides, Javadoc overviews, and generated diagrams/resources.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved OpenAI provider robustness (follow-up tool-call handling, timeout handling, BadRequest recovery, and corrected token/tool limit constants).</li>
  <li>Hardened command execution tools (denylist configuration/init fixes, improved checks, and clearer errors).</li>
  <li>Fixed act processing and defaults (scanDir/rootDir handling, act template loading/parsing, inheritance/placeholders, and CLI/maven non-interactive configuration).</li>
  <li>Addressed Grype-reported security issues (CVE-2025-48924 / GHSA-j288-q9x7-2f5v and CVE-2021-26291 / GHSA-2f88-5hg8-9x2x).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Refined Ghostwriter processing pipeline (shared module processing in an abstract processor, deterministic template application, and normalized prompt/tool output line endings).</li>
  <li>Streamlined Bindex prompt/build flows and updated APIs for clarity and maintainability.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Expanded and refreshed CLI, Maven plugin, Act, and Ghostwriter documentation (usage examples, troubleshooting, configuration semantics, and site navigation).</li>
  <li>Added/updated Javadoc overview pages across modules and improved generated site assets (icons, manifests, links).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Project setup and packaging updates across modules, including configurator/version alignment and assembly descriptor improvements.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-03-14">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved CLI help output and Act listing (including returning Act <code>description</code>).</li>
  <li>Added URL-based Acts location support.</li>
  <li>Added command-line properties replacement support in <code>CommandFunctionTools</code>.</li>
  <li>Added <code>sonar-tests</code> and project-specific <code>sonar-fix</code> Acts, plus unit-test creation guidance tags.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed <code>callRestApi</code> handling for error responses.</li>
  <li>Corrected command denylist checking to validate the entire command line.</li>
  <li>Fixed non-recursive mode processing.</li>
  <li>Fixed Act/template edge cases (properties inheritance, input formatting/double formatting, <code>%%.</code> escaping, NPEs, log path).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved Act prompt parsing, <code>scanDir</code> resolution, and concurrency/CLI option handling across Ghostwriter and Acts.</li>
  <li>Refactored production code to improve testability; adopted <code>ToolFunction</code> interface and adjusted visibility where needed.</li>
  <li>General cleanup: optimized imports, removed unused code/rules.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated Javadocs and prompts/instructions (including OS name in project information and guidance on running Sonar before fetching reports).</li>
  <li>Updated Act templates (commit/help/release-notes/sonar*).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added <code>jacoco-maven-plugin</code> and <code>junit-jupiter-params</code>; expanded automated test coverage.</li>
  <li>Iterated on Sonar fixes generated by automation (including a revert and merge sync).</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.2" date="2026-03-23">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved Bindex/assembly flows: updated picker selection and repository/register behavior; enhanced assembly prompting (including OS info in instructions) and response logging.</li>
  <li>Extended unit test coverage across modules (bindex-core builder/tool happy-path tests, project layout tests, OpenAI tool invocation tests, gw-maven-plugin tests, and additional CLI/assembly coverage).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed Act loader robustness (null-safe formatting fallback; handling missing custom act directory; correct absolute-path and URL handling).</li>
  <li>Fixed reactor build scanning behavior for <code>gw-maven-plugin</code>.</li>
  <li>Fixed assembly command logging and inputs log wiring.</li>
  <li>Fixed PlantUML Maven plugin definition/configuration and corrected site configuration (<code>site.toml</code>).</li>
  <li>Improved Bindex registry connection handling and updated CLI defaults for model/dir and logging.</li>
  <li>Updated dependency versions (including Grype-reported vulnerable dependencies).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Standardized on <code>project.dir</code> usage across CLI, Bindex, Assembly, and Ghostwriter processors.</li>
  <li>Removed effective POM model building/requirements and cleaned up unused Maven-related dependencies.</li>
  <li>Refined variable naming in Ghostwriter models and removed internal helper types (e.g., <code>ToolHandlingResult</code>).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated documentation for bindex-core, bindex-maven-plugin, assembly-maven-plugin, and guidance defaults/scanDir configuration.</li>
  <li>Improved and expanded project site content and Act templates (help/commit/site).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated plugin management defaults, logback rollover configuration, and various generated <code>bindex.json</code> metadata refreshes.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.3" date="2026-03-30">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added support for partial replacements in the <code>write_file_to_file_system</code> tool.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed <code>logInputs</code> property constant/name usage across CLI, Maven plugins, providers, and assembly (including inputs log propagation and setter naming).</li>
  <li>Fixed Ghostwriter property constants and scan exclusion handling; corrected GW command instruction property usage.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated documentation.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added/expanded automated tests (CLI property loading, ProjectProcessor module processing, assembly and builder coverage).</li>
  <li>Refreshed <code>bindex.json</code> metadata files.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
