<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-03-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Initial Machai CLI release, including core commands and configuration support.</li>
  <li>Act workflow: run Acts from built-in and custom act directories, with TOML-based act templates, inheritance, placeholders, defaults, and improved error handling.</li>
  <li>AI/GenAI provider integrations and tooling: OpenAI provider improvements (timeouts, BadRequest recovery, logging, token/tool limit fixes), plus provider stubs (Claude/Gemini) and CodeMie integration updates.</li>
  <li>Function tools framework: ServiceLoader-based discovery, REST and web-page fetch tools (incl. basic auth and text-only extraction), command execution tooling, and process termination support.</li>
  <li>Project layout and scanning improvements: better rootDir/scanDir handling, Maven/Gradle/JS layouts, deterministic processing, module traversal, and denylist-based command security checks.</li>
  <li>Assembly and packaging: assembly command and descriptors, delivery pack/zip creation, and Maven plugin goals and defaults.</li>
  <li>Bindex capabilities: schema, repositories and function tools, generation/search improvements, layering and scoring, and builders for multiple project types.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved robustness for act processing (template parsing, defaults, inherit placeholders, missing config handling) and scanning behavior.</li>
  <li>Security and vulnerability fixes, including Grype-reported CVEs (GHSA-j288-q9x7-2f5v / CVE-2025-48924 and GHSA-2f88-5hg8-9x2x / CVE-2021-26291).</li>
  <li>Multiple CLI/plugin fixes across options, logging, packaging, and provider request handling (e.g., follow-up requests, timeouts, and token refresh).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Refined Act prompt flow and normalized tool output/newlines; improved shared module processing in file processors.</li>
  <li>Provider and tooling refactors (e.g., OpenAI client handling and adapter extraction) to simplify integration points.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Expanded CLI, plugin, and Act documentation with practical examples; updated site content, navigation, icons, and manifests.</li>
  <li>Improved Javadoc guidance and generated documentation structure across modules.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Version and dependency updates leading to the 1.0.0 release; packaging and build configuration cleanups.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-03-14">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added <code>conf</code> command and persistent configuration support (save/load system properties).</li>
  <li>Added AeProvider and bundled AE recipes into the distribution/JAR; moved recipes into <code>genai-client</code> resources.</li>
  <li>Improved guidance-driven file processing (process files based on <code>@guidance</code> tags) and added <code>--dir</code>/<code>--root</code> options (plus <code>--clean</code>) to the processing workflow.</li>
  <li>Added URL registration parameter support to Picker.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved compatibility with OpenAI-compatible providers; fixed prompts/model settings for CodeMie + gpt-4o-2024-08-06.</li>
  <li>Fixed path/property issues (e.g., <code>&lt;ae.dir&gt;</code>/<code>&lt;aeDir&gt;</code>) and adjusted plugin execution safety (set threadSafe=false; fixed parent project processing).</li>
  <li>Resolved template/guidance formatting issues (removed extra tags; fixed <code>---</code> handling) and corrected file path usage in markdown reviewing.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Package and naming cleanups (e.g., BIndex -&gt; Bindex) and general import/output message polish.</li>
  <li>Embedding logic improvements to better support non-OpenAPI services.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated README and site docs; refreshed AE recipes documentation and generated docs via gw process.</li>
  <li>Added/updated <code>package-info.java</code> across packages for improved API documentation.</li>
  <li>Renamed <code>docs</code> command to <code>process</code> and updated documentation accordingly.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Routine documentation regeneration and repository maintenance commits (gw process updates).</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.2" date="2026-03-23">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated CLI commands.</li>
  <li>Adjusted <code>act</code>/<code>assembly</code> command behavior.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed configuration property names (including GenAI model property) and updated documentation accordingly.</li>
  <li>Fixed <code>AssemblyCommand</code> input logging (<code>setInputsLog</code>).</li>
  <li>Corrected project folder naming/structure.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated <code>bindex.json</code> files.</li>
  <li>Removed unused Maven-related dependencies.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated README and general documentation.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.3" date="2026-03-30">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Improved <code>act</code> command prompt input handling.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed guidance tag definition and PlantUML Maven plugin configuration.</li>
  <li>Fixed CLI/config property constant usage in commands (<code>GWCommand</code>, <code>ActCommand</code>).</li>
  <li>Fixed CLI property loading and missing config handling (with tests).</li>
  <li>Fixed Machai CLI GenAI manager references.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Removed system properties file loading.</li>
  <li>Removed assembly command and bindex assembly support.</li>
  <li>Removed <code>gw.guidance</code> from <code>gw</code> goal.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Documentation</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated documentation and Javadoc (including overview formatting guidance).</li>
</ul>

<h3>Chores</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Updated CLI commands/tests and addressed Sonar issues.</li>
  <li>Updated <code>bindex.json</code> files.</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
