<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/2.0.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-2.0.0.xsd">
  <body>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-03-09">
      <action dev="dev" type="add">
        <![CDATA[
<h2>Features</h2>
<ul>
  <li>CLI commands for indexing and assembly workflows (bindex, register, assembly), including debug/overwrite flags and directory targeting.</li>
  <li>BIndex generation and update support (including Maven and Python/JavaScript builders) with schema evolution (layers, scores, constructors, examples).</li>
  <li>Vector/semantic search improvements: classification vs description embeddings, score thresholds, filtering by language/domains/integration, and better result reporting.</li>
  <li>GenAI integration enhancements: provider abstraction, multi-call functional tools, prompt templates via resource bundles, and parent/sub-module processing.</li>
  <li>New Maven plugins/modules added, including ghostwriter-maven-plugin and assembly-maven-plugin.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Fixes</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Resolved issues in prompt templates and guidance handling (markdown guidance tag, guidance file pathing, Java prompt generation).</li>
  <li>Fixed project layout/path handling and root-directory file processing; improved project structure description generation.</li>
  <li>Fixed BIndex/plugin issues (NPE, required property handling, effective model retrieval, plugin property names) and corrected JS/Python edge cases (file extension filters, private Python packages).</li>
  <li>Fixed logging and output behavior (inputs log paths/location, debug mode behavior, stream closing).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Refactoring</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Extracted/reshaped core abstractions (GenAIProvider, FunctionTools, Reviewer classes, ProjectLayout vs BindexBuilder, AssemblyCommand).</li>
  <li>Renamed/reorganized modules and directories (e.g., bindex-core naming, CLI folder rename, documents module movements) and general cleanup.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Documentation</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Substantial README and site documentation updates, including diagrams, images, and improved Javadoc coverage across main sources.</li>
  <li>Added and refined prompt/recipe documentation and examples for supported workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Chores</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Release and build metadata updates (pom descriptions, javadoc plugin config, versioning and release tags).</li>
  <li>Added/updated project assets (logos, screenshots) and housekeeping changes (tests, file renames, excludes).</li>
</ul>
        ]]>
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
